ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER REACT & REDUX, JAVASCRIPT, RUBY ON RAILS, MERN, POSTGRESQL

PROFILE

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, selfpublished a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Developer specializing in React & Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer & cat instagram follower.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT FEBRUARY 2020 – JUNE 2020

React & Redux, JavaScript, Ruby & Rails, SQL and PostgreSQL

SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA BACHELOR OF ARTS AUGUST 2008 – MAY 2012

Social Behavioral Sciences - 3.8 GPA

CONTACT



Eric.Saikit.Cheung@gmail.com



646.637.1808



https://ericskcheung.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung



erock_esquire

EXPERIENCE

HIES INC • FRONT-END DEVELOPER • JULY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

Designed & rebuilt HIES company website using React JS & Redux, & SASS/SCSS.

- **Redesigned** & built entire HIES company website to be modern, manageable, and business & user-friendly. Utilized React Router for URL address routing.
- **Incorporated** PIXI.js to create realistic moving water effect on hero image. Recreated original hero image using Adobe Photoshop for higher resolution.
- **Organized** over 20 company services into 4 manageable categories, composed descriptions for each service, and added search feature for services.

CURBALERT • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • JUNE 2020

React JS & Redux, Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to post images & details of unwanted items on street onto a public map.

- **Engineered** codebase synchronizing Geolocation & Google Geocode API to obtain coordinates used to incorporate Google Directions API, allowing users to see directions and distance to items.
- **Collaborated** functionality between AWS S3 Cloud & Rails Active Storage to store user post images on cloud bucket through Rails back-end API.

HANGOUTS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • MAY 2020

React JS and Ruby on Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to plan meetups at location calculated to be equal distance between all participants.

- **Architected** a Rails back-end call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user current coordinates and requested coordinates, before plotting to Leaflet API map.
- **Composed** function to calculate a midpoint location between groups of users from coordinate data retrieved by Geolocation & Google Geocode API.

BANZAI PHRESH • OWNER/SOLE PROPRIETOR • APRIL 2016 – JUNE 2018

Owned & operated restaurants at two locations. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business.

- Ala Moana Mall Honolulu, HI. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.
- Smorgasburg Market Brooklyn, NY. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.
- Managed logistical problems such as strict time management, division of labor, inventory tracking & ordering deadlines, and maintaining quality of service & food.

KINGS OF FORTUNE · AUTHOR/WRITER · 2014

Self-published an action/adventure fiction novel.

• Received 5 of 5 stars on San Francisco Book Review, 4 of 5 stars on Portland Book Review, and featured review on Kirkus magazine.